Episode 8 "A Gift
More Lovely Than Jewels"
Freshly caught today!
Kyros, may I look at that stall, too?
Yes, of course.
These spices are for Toppo.
These flower seeds are for Johan.
This bracelet is lovely, too!
These are all gifts for
everyone back at the castle.
Well, it's fun.
And you can't really say anything
about anyone else, Kyros.
All you've bought are gifts for me.
Looks like we should stop by the carriage
to drop things off, don't you think?
Yes, you're right.
Is this... the artisans quarter?
This shop is a purveyor to the royal family.
I've agreed to meet Luiphon here.
Thank you for visiting our shop,
Count Granado.
Giovanni! It's been a while, hasn't it?
Is Luiphon here?
Yes, he's on the second floor taking a nap.
He summons me here, then takes a nap?
Marie, please wait here for me.
He's got a habit of sleeping naked.
I will.
They must process precious
stones at this shop.
I wonder what these are.
These are fragments produced during
the design-cutting process.
They come from high quality jewels.
Really? They're beautiful.
If you thread them, they can also
be used to make modest accessories.
As you are the count's guest, we'll happily
gift you as many as you like.
What?!
All I did was follow Lord Kyros here,
and he'll give them to me for free?
What a beautiful green.
I-If I were to buy these,
how much would they cost?
What?
Well...
Something close to this amount.
They aren't inexpensive, but at this price...
I-I'll take these, please.
And I will, of course, pay for them.
Understood.
I've hardly ever even touched any jewels.
I never imagined I'd buy any myself.
Why hello, Miss! Have you bought
yourself something nice there?
What? Could this be that
"being picked up" thing?
Yes, thank you!
But I'm here with someone,
so if you'll excuse me!
What? What is this person
like? Is he handsome?
H-He's wonderful! Very much so!
In what way? His looks? His
personality? Do you share interests?
Have you kissed?
H-His looks and personality
are both wonderful!
We share interests,
and he's a wonderful fiancé!
And as for kissing, we are
likely to do so very soon!
What? L-Lord Kyros?
Death
by Cuteness...
S-Sorry.
And you, Luiphon! Weren't you
napping on the second floor?
Hey, my dear Marie! It's been a while.
It's me, Prince Luiphon!
O-Once again, this man has...
Now, then.
I know it's sudden, but let's finish up
the business that I called you here for.
This is in celebration of your betrothal.
A ruby?
No. A pink diamond?
But it's very red for one of those.
It's an incredibly rare red diamond!
Search the world and you won't
find another of this size.
It's magnificent.
It must be a national treasure.
Indeed!
During the war, this rare item was used to
negotiate alliances with other nations.
Though ever since then, it has
slept in the royal palace treasure vault.
You can have it for eighty million euiro.
I'll give you a friends discount.
You're telling me to buy it?
I convinced all those strait-laced old men
in a meeting of the royal family, you know?
I said, "If any of us royals were to wear it,
our people would say to stop
wasting their taxes and revolt."
Is that how it works?
Though if I said it was a gift for Count
Granado, no one would be able to complain.
What?
Sweet Marie, the Granado family's wealth
currently exceeds that of the royal family.
The highway that the then
Margrave Granado laid down...
The checkpoints and harbor he built
to collect taxes from the merchants...
Duchess Liu Liu and Kyros'
skillful mercantile abilities...
That's how the House of Granado
obtained their immense wealth.
These days, nobility alone
doesn't guarantee a life of ease.
If they can't change with the times, even the
most distinguished families will quickly fall.
Like Baron Shaderan's family did.
He doesn't mean that as a slight towards me.
Wealth is a weapon. One used to protect
one's people and other precious things.
Yes, and as a member of the House of Granado,
I will be diligent about
never neglecting my studies.
Marie.
I'll make it 70 million!
Dear Kyros, you have been
searching, haven't you?
For a gem that matches the color of her
hair, the most beautiful jewel in the world!
I wanted it to be a surprise
for the betrothal ceremony!
It's just that the distinct charm
of this color is so unique...
I thought of you right away.
Does he mean the color of my hair?
But it's usually something
that people disdain and avoid.
Thank you, Luiphon, for searching out
something so perfectly suited to us.
You're very welcome.
But it'll still take a few
days to turn it into a ring.
Thank you for before.
When I heard that you'd been looking
for a gem the color of my hair,
it made me very happy.
Y-Yes. I hoped it might delight you.
I thought that your kindness was simply
you being considerate towards me,
so I've always shied away from it.
But now, I understand how you feel.
This is a gift for you.
Wh-What?
When I was picking out presents for
everyone, I secretly bought this.
Will you accept it?
As long as it isn't an imposition!
It looks good, right?
You look quite dashing!
And, actually, I also have this.
Emerald fragments?
Yes.
I thought that it might look nice if
I sewed them on the ends like this.
And the last one is for me.
You like emeralds?
No.
It's only that I thought they
matched the color of your eyes.
My eyes?
The moment I thought
they looked like his eyes...
I suddenly wanted those fragments.
I dearly wanted to make them my own.
It's a little hot, isn't it?
I'm going to open the window.
Watch out!
What happened? Did something
out there cause you concern?
N-No, it's nothing.
I'm sorry. I wasn't thinking properly.
Today, I was so happy.
Because you held my hands.
I've always had a complex about
my large, unlovely hands.
Your hands are charming.
I like holding hands with you very much.
I like it, too.
If it's only my hands that you like,
then please, push me away.
Not at all.
I'm so happy.
Then trade places with me.
Sister?
Why are you there? That spot belongs to me.
Trade places with me.
Trade places!
Yes...
This is how it should be.
So then, why...
Why do I feel...
so cold?
M-Marie?
P-Please stop the carriage!
No! To a doctor, immediately!
It's cold. So cold... it hurts.
It's cold.
It hurts.
Sister...
I'm right here, Marie.
How's that? Does it feel better?
Thank you, Sister.
It's all right. It's just
a cold in your ears.
They said that if you sleep
a lot, you'll get better.
Where are Mama and Papa?
They both said they're busy with work.
That's why your big sister's
going to read you a book!
It's your favorite, Marie!
"The Raggedy Red Cat"!
"Some other time in some other place,"
"a raggedy red cat lived in a town."
"Say, little cat, what's your name?"
"None of your business, you idiot!
Why would I have a name anyway?"
"I'm just a raggedy old cat!"
"Don't you wanna know why I'm raggedy?"
"I know why. It's because you're red, right?"
"You should go on a journey, too."
"If a cat lies around like
trash, it becomes trash."
"If trash meows like a cat,
then it becomes a cat."
"And..."
"if that cat goes traveling,
then it becomes a traveling cat!"
Anastasia!
I told you not to enter
Marie's room, didn't I?
You don't listen no matter how
many times you're told, do you?
Grandmother Sasha...
I'm her big sister, so I
have to make Marie better!
This nonsense won't make
her better, you fool!
And your translation is entirely incompetent!
Learning it properly is
for Marie's sake as well.
How many times have I told you?
I-I'm sorry!
Marie.
Forget what Anastasia has
read you from this book.
You will learn it just as it is written.
Is it time for lessons?
My body still isn't...
You are the smartest of
everyone in this house.
That's why educating you is
the most efficient choice.
But Sister says she likes
words from Ipsandros, too.
That has nothing to do with anything.
You will recite this and learn Ipsian
while you are still four years old.
And you will master Flarian
before you turn six years old.
Yes, I will.
I love this story from Ipsandros, but...
It's cold. It hurts.
Sister, where are you?
Sister... help me!
Sister...
Lord Kyros?
Are you awake, Marie?
Why am I...
You collapsed with a fever.
The doctor said it's likely from exhaustion.
A fever?
Don't push yourself yet. You were
groaning so much in your sleep.
I was dreaming.
But where are we?
The napping room in the castle.
It's the closest one to the gate.
Oh, and please don't worry.
I left changing your clothes and wiping
your sweat to the maids and left the room.
I swear to you that I also did
not sneak under the covers.
I-I wasn't worried about any of that.
Thanks to everyone's help,
I think my fever has gone down.
How long have I been...
You've slept for nearly half
a day. It's almost dawn.
Don't tell me... Lord Kyros,
does this mean you haven't slept?
You looked after me all night?
I didn't do anything much.
I couldn't have slept for worrying
anyway. Don't let it trouble you.
But...
Marie, this soup is very nourishing.
It isn't bitter at all.
I could eat it even if it was bitter.
This brings back memories
from when I was little.
Your big sister will feed
you! Now, open wide!
Marie?
Marie, here.
I-I'm so sorry! It isn't what you think!
A long time ago, my sister
looked after me and...
Your sister looked after you?
Yes, but that was when we were very little.
Now that he mentions it,
when did I start eating alone?
Was it after Grandmother Sasha passed away?
Is the soup not enough for you?
There's some biscuit cookies here.
Biscuit cookies?
Ever since Grandmother died,
Mother started treating me as
though I were no more than smoke.
Marie! You must be hungry, right?
I brought you some biscuit cookies.
I can't. Mama said I
can't eat anything today.
It's because I got taller again.
Don't worry about any of that!
Here!
It's delicious.
Marie, are you all right?
My beautiful, kind older sister...
If she had lived, then instead of
someone like me, Lord Kyros would...
I'll go fetch the doctor!
Wait!
Please don't go.
I beg of you, stay here with me.
Marie.
Don't worry. I'll come right back.
Has being sick made you feel forlorn?
That isn't it.
I just don't want to be apart
from you for even a moment.
If you're doing this out of gratitude
for my nursing you, you don't have to.
How could my selfishness
serve as thanks towards you?
Because...
you keep saying things that make me happy.
When did I start being able to
look him in the eye like this?
Even when I never lifted my gaze,
he was always watching over me.
I love your eyes.
Before, when you were kind
to me, it made me hesitate,
but now... it only makes me happy.
I'm going to be filled to the brim
with this feeling of happiness.
I... love you.
You are...
Marie...
From the first moment I
met you, I've loved you.
Once, I would have rejected
those words, but now...
Yes.
I'm so happy I think I may cry.
I am delighted that my love is reciprocated,
but also, that you're saying these
things to me of your own accord...
nothing could possibly make me happier.
I have to tell the doctor that you're awake.
I'll come right back, so please
stay there in bed and wait for me.
In bed...
I-I'll wait right here!
I-I didn't mean it like that!
What? Oh, I'm sorry! I jumped to conclusions!
No, I'm the one who's sorry.
Well, then!
Lord Kyros?
What happened?
I-It's nothing.
He was skipping and missed
a step on the stairs.
Honestly. What a fool.
Mio! Welcome home!
I've just returned. There is a small
but urgent matter to attend to.
What is it?
Master.
I've brought a guest to the reception hall.
Is it really all right for me to come, too?
Yes.
It won't be pleasant, but it's something
you should hear with your own ears.
It concerns a member of your
family, Anastasia Shaderan.
I'll take over.
This is the current lord, Kyros Granado.
Raise your head, Jacob.
This man... was the driver of the
carriage that Lady Anastasia rode in.
The one where my sister died in an accident?
Jacob...
I hear that you came here years ago from the
Bandelee Islands in order to earn money.
Was it you?
Did you kill Anastasia Shaderan?
It's been a long time since I became
the Granado Castle huntsman,
but I never imagined I'd be charged
with a duty like this one.
Next time, "In Pursuit
of Anastasia's Spirit."
Episode 9 "In Pursuit
of Anastasia's Spirit"
Don't miss it.